Neil H. Landman Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Neil H. Landman Archives
1982-1982
IPAR.001043
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
2
The archives of Neil H. Landman including locality information, photographs, and copies of notebooks. This collection focuses on Landman's work with scaphitid ammonoids.
Landman, Neil H.
Biographical Sketch
Neil, H Landman received his Ph.D. from Yale University in 1982 ("Ontogeny and Evolution of Late Cretaceous (Turonian-Santonian) Scaphites") as a student of Karl Waage. Curator of Paleontology at AMNH and curatorial associate at the Yale Peabody Museum.
Description of the Material
Includes photocopies of his 1977 and 1980 field notebooks, as well as some miscellaneous locality information, and photographs and drawings of specimens.
Connecticut; New York; Field notebooks; Locality information; Photographs; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Photographs & Drawings, 1982; Series I
  - Specimens. Photographs and drawings of specimens., 001046
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black & white photos & negatives of scaphitid hooks; Cretaceous Fox Hills Fm, South Dakota (see repr. 5003, Landman & Waage, 1993) Black & white negatives & prints, 000679
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black & white negatives & photos of scaphitid ammonoids (Discoscaphites conradi, D. gulosus), Fox Hills Fm, South Dakota; see Landman & Waage, 1993 Black & white negatives & photos, 000682
    - drawing. Suture drawings of scaphitid ammonoids (Hoploscaphites nicolletii, H. comprimus, Discoscaphites conradi, D. gulosus, D. rossi) from Fox Hills Fm, South Dakota; see repr. 5003, Landman & Waage, 1993, 000680
- Miscellaneous, 1982; Series II
  Scope and Contents
  Miscellaneous Archives from Neil. H Landman including Locality information and field notes encompassing his time at Yale.
  - Field Notes. Copies of Field Notebooks., 001048
    - Field notes. Photo copy of field notebook for dissertation collections of Scaphites from the Upper Cretaceous: Wyoming, Montana, South Dakota. 1977, 1978, 000326
    - Field notes. Photo copy of field notebook for dissertation collections of Scaphites from the Upper Cretaceous: Wyoming, Montana, South Dakota., 1980; 000327
  - Locality Information. Locality Information associated with Neil H Landman encompassing his time at Yale., 001047
    - Locality information. locality information; South Dakota, Cretaceous. Annotated xerox of topo map., 2000; 000745
    - locality information. Locality information for Unio from Hell Creek Fm, South Dakota, 2000; 000700
  - Miscellaneous., 001049
    - Maximum-length measurements for all Hoploscaphites nicolletii & H. comprimus specimens from type Fox Hills Fm area, South & North Dakota, 1998; 000684